[

  {
    "topic" : "IRREGULAR VERBS PART 01",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "surgir", "answers" : ["arise, arose, arisen"] },
      { "question" : "acordar", "answers" : ["awake, awoke, awoken"] },
      { "question" : "ser, estar", "answers" : ["be, was, wore, been"] },
      { "question" : "tornar-se", "answers" : ["become, became, become"] },
      { "question" : "começar, iniciar", "answers" : ["begin, began, begun"] },
      { "question" : "apostar", "answers" : ["bet, bet, bet"] },
      { "question" : "morder", "answers" : ["bite, bit, bitten"] },
      { "question" : "quebrar", "answers" : ["break, broke, broken"] },
      { "question" : "trazer", "answers" : ["bring, brought, brought"] },
      { "question" : "transmitir", "answers" : ["broadcast, broadcast, broadcast"] },
      { "question" : "construir", "answers" : ["build, built, built"] },
      { "question" : "comprar", "answers" : ["buy, bought, bought"] },
      { "question" : "pegar, apanhar, capturar", "answers" : ["catch, caught, caught"] },
      { "question" : "escolher", "answers" : ["choose, chose, chosen"] },
      { "question" : "vir", "answers" : ["come, came, come"] },
      { "question" : "custar", "answers" : ["cost, cost, cost"] },
      { "question" : "cortar", "answers" : ["cut, cut, cut"] },
      { "question" : "negociar", "answers" : ["deal, dealt, dealt"] },
      { "question" : "fazer", "answers" : ["do, did, done"] },
      { "question" : "desenhar", "answers" : ["draw, drew, drawn"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "IRREGULAR VERBS PART 02",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "make", "answers" : ["made"] },
      { "question" : "write", "answers" : ["wrote"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "Education",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "advanced", "answers" : ["avancado"] },
      { "question" : "beginner", "answers" : ["iniciante"] },
      { "question" : "biology", "answers" : ["biologia"] },
      { "question" : "blackboard", "answers" : ["lousa"] },
      { "question" : "board", "answers" : ["quadro de avisos"] },
      { "question" : "book", "answers" : ["livro"] },
      { "question" : "bookshelf", "answers" : ["estante de livros"] },
      { "question" : "chemistry", "answers" : ["quimica"] },
      { "question" : "class", "answers" : ["classe"] },
      { "question" : "classmate", "answers" : ["colega de classe"] },
      { "question" : "classroom", "answers" : ["sala de aula"] },
      { "question" : "clever", "answers" : ["inteligente"] },
      { "question" : "coach", "answers" : ["treinador"] },
      { "question" : "course", "answers" : ["curso"] },
      { "question" : "mark", "answers" : ["marca", "nota"] },
      { "question" : "science", "answers" : ["ciencia"] },
      { "question" : "subject", "answers" : ["assunto"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "Family and Friends",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "aunt", "answers" : ["tia"] },
      { "question" : "uncle", "answers" : ["tio"] },
      { "question" : "boy", "answers" : ["menino"] },
      { "question" : "brother", "answers" : ["irmao"] },
      { "question" : "child", "answers" : ["crianca"] },
      { "question" : "cousin", "answers" : ["primo"] },
      { "question" : "dad", "answers" : ["papai", "pai"] },
      { "question" : "daughter", "answers" : ["filha"] },
      { "question" : "grandchild", "answers" : ["neto"] },
      { "question" : "grandson", "answers" : ["neto"] },
      { "question" : "granddaughter", "answers" : ["neta"] },
      { "question" : "grandfather", "answers" : ["avô"] },
      { "question" : "grandmother", "answers" : ["avo"] },
      { "question" : "grandparent", "answers" : ["avô", "avó"] },
      { "question" : "guest", "answers" : ["convidado"] },
      { "question" : "guy", "answers" : ["cara"] },
      { "question" : "Miss", "answers" : ["sentir falta"] },
      { "question" : "Mr", "answers" : ["senhor"] },
      { "question" : "Ms", "answers" : ["senhora"] },
      { "question" : "mum", "answers" : ["mae"] },
      { "question" : "neighbour", "answers" : ["vizinho"] },
      { "question" : "son", "answers" : ["filho"] },
      { "question" : "surname", "answers" : ["ultimo nome"] },
      { "question" : "teenager", "answers" : ["adolescente"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "Food and Drink",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "bake", "answers" : ["assar"] },
      { "question" : "biscuit", "answers" : ["bolacha", "biscoito"] },
      { "question" : "boil", "answers" : ["ferver"] },
      { "question" : "boiled", "answers" : ["fervido"] },
      { "question" : "bottle", "answers" : ["garrafa"] },
      { "question" : "bowl", "answers" : ["tigela"] },
      { "question" : "butter", "answers" : ["manteiga"] },
      { "question" : "candy", "answers" : ["doce", "chocolate"] },
      { "question" : "carrot", "answers" : ["cenoura"] },
      { "question" : "chilli", "answers" : ["pimenta"] },
      { "question" : "chip", "answers" : ["batata frita"] },
      { "question" : "cream", "answers" : ["creme de leite", "creme"] },
      { "question" : "cup", "answers" : ["xicara"] },
      { "question" : "cut", "answers" : ["cortar"] },
      { "question" : "fork", "answers" : ["garfo"] },
      { "question" : "fridge", "answers" : ["geladeira", "refrigerador"] },
      { "question" : "fried", "answers" : ["frito"] },
      { "question" : "garlic", "answers" : ["alho"] },
      { "question" : "glass", "answers" : ["vidro"] },
      { "question" : "grape", "answers" : ["uva"] },
      { "question" : "grilled", "answers" : ["grelhado"] },
      { "question" : "honey", "answers" : ["mel"] },
      { "question" : "jam", "answers" : ["geleia"] },
      { "question" : "knife", "answers" : ["faca"] },
      { "question" : "meal", "answers" : ["refeicao"] },
      { "question" : "meat", "answers" : ["carne"] },
      { "question" : "melon", "answers" : ["melao"] },
      { "question" : "mushroom", "answers" : ["cogumelo"] },
      { "question" : "oil", "answers" : ["oleo"] },
      { "question" : "onion", "answers" : ["cebola"] },
      { "question" : "pear", "answers" : ["pera"] },
      { "question" : "pepper", "answers" : ["pimenta", "pimentao"] },
      { "question" : "picnic", "answers" : ["piquenique"] },
      { "question" : "potato", "answers" : ["batata"] },
      { "question" : "rice", "answers" : ["arroz"] },
      { "question" : "roast", "answers" : ["assar", "assado"] },
      { "question" : "salt", "answers" : ["sal"] },
      { "question" : "sauce", "answers" : ["molho"] },
      { "question" : "sausage", "answers" : ["salsicha", "linguica"] },
      { "question" : "slice", "answers" : ["fatia", "fatiar"] },
      { "question" : "snack", "answers" : ["petisco"] },
      { "question" : "soup", "answers" : ["sopa"] },
      { "question" : "steak", "answers" : ["bife"] },
      { "question" : "strawberry", "answers" : ["morango"] },
      { "question" : "sugar", "answers" : ["acucar"] },
      { "question" : "sweet", "answers" : ["doce"] },
      { "question" : "tea", "answers" : ["cha"] },
      { "question" : "thirsty", "answers" : ["estar com sede" , "com sede", "sedento"] },
      { "question" : "toast", "answers" : ["torrar", "torrada"] },
      { "question" : "waiter", "answers" : ["garcom"] },
      { "question" : "waitress", "answers" : ["garconete"] },
      { "question" : "wash up", "answers" : ["lavar as maos"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "NEW WORDS PART 01",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "ever", "answers" : ["at any time", "alguma vez", "nunca"] },
      { "question" : "always", "answers" : ["every time", "sempre"] },
      { "question" : "proud", "answers" : ["satisfeito", "orgulhoso"] },
      { "question" : "brainstorm", "answers" : ["ideas", "ideias"] },
      { "question" : "adventure", "answers" : ["aventura"] },
      { "question" : "arrest", "answers" : ["prender"] },
      { "question" : "against", "answers" : ["contra"] },
      { "question" : "puzzle", "answers" : ["enigma", "misterio"] },
      { "question" : "knock", "answers" : ["bater"] },
      { "question" : "rushed", "answers" : ["apressado"] },
      { "question" : "pale", "answers" : ["palido"] },
      { "question" : "untidy", "answers" : ["desarrumado"] },
      { "question" : "frightened", "answers" : ["assustado"] },
      { "question" : "breathing", "answers" : ["respiracao"] },
      { "question" : "breathe", "answers" : ["respirar"] },
      { "question" : "lung", "answers" : ["pulmao"] },
      { "question" : "heavily", "answers" : ["muito"] },
      { "question" : "desperate", "answers" : ["desesperado"] },
      { "question" : "desperately", "answers" : ["desesperadamente"] },
      { "question" : "scandal", "answers" : ["escandalo"] },
      { "question" : "obvious", "answers" : ["obvio"] },
      { "question" : "obviously", "answers" : ["obviamente"] },
      { "question" : "charge", "answers" : ["encargo", "acusacao"] },
      { "question" : "murder", "answers" : ["assassinato"] },
      { "question" : "tall", "answers" : ["alto"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "NEW WORDS PART 02",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "thin", "answers" : ["magro"] },
      { "question" : "finger", "answers" : ["dedo"] },
      { "question" : "fierce", "answers" : ["feroz" , "selvagem", "furioso"] },
      { "question" : "visitor", "answers" : ["visitante", "visita", "turista"] },
      { "question" : "illness", "answers" : ["doenca"] },
      { "question" : "seem", "answers" : ["parecer"] },
      { "question" : "seemed", "answers" : ["parecia"] },
      { "question" : "headline", "answers" : ["manchete", "noticia principal", "principal noticia"] },
      { "question" : "hold", "answers" : ["segurar"] },
      { "question" : "held", "answers" : ["segurado"] },
      { "question" : "firm", "answers" : ["firme"] },
      { "question" : "soft", "answers" : ["suave", "macio"] },
      { "question" : "rarely", "answers" : ["raramente"] },
      { "question" : "elderly", "answers" : ["idoso"] },
      { "question" : "housekeeper", "answers" : ["empregada"] },
      { "question" : "timber", "answers" : ["madeira"] },
      { "question" : "wood", "answers" : ["madeira"] },
      { "question" : "burnt", "answers" : ["queimado"] },
      { "question" : "burn", "answers" : ["queimar"] },
      { "question" : "flame", "answers" : ["chama"] },
      { "question" : "keep", "answers" : ["manter"] },
      { "question" : "kept", "answers" : ["manteve"] },
      { "question" : "stick", "answers" : ["colar", "grudar"] },
      { "question" : "leading", "answers" : ["conduzindo"] },
      { "question" : "lead", "answers" : ["conduzir"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "NEW WORDS PART 03",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "led", "answers" : ["conduziu"] },
      { "question" : "marker", "answers" : ["marcardor"] },
      { "question" : "towards", "answers" : ["em direcao", "em direcao a"] },
      { "question" : "flesh", "answers" : ["carne", "carne do ser humano"] },
      { "question" : "skin", "answers" : ["pele"] },
      { "question" : "among", "answers" : ["entre", "no meio", "no meio de"] },
      { "question" : "fear", "answers" : ["medo", "temer"] },
      { "question" : "worst", "answers" : ["o pior"] },
      { "question" : "reply", "answers" : ["responder"] },
      { "question" : "replied", "answers" : ["respondeu"] },
      { "question" : "straight", "answers" : ["reto", "em linha reta"] },
      { "question" : "noise", "answers" : ["barulho"] },
      { "question" : "fight", "answers" : ["lutar", "brigar"] },
      { "question" : "act", "answers" : ["agir", "comportar-se"] },
      { "question" : "worth", "answers" : ["valer a pena"] },
      { "question" : "matter", "answers" : ["assunto", "materia"] },
      { "question" : "spread", "answers" : ["espelhar", "propagar", "estender", "expandir"] },
      { "question" : "stairs", "answers" : ["escada"] },
      { "question" : "poverty", "answers" : ["pobreza"] },
      { "question" : "advertising", "answers" : ["publicidade"] },
      { "question" : "charity", "answers" : ["caridade", "doacao"] },
      { "question" : "staff", "answers" : ["pessoal", "quadro de funcionarios"] },
      { "question" : "witness", "answers" : ["testemunha"] },
      { "question" : "kindness", "answers" : ["bondade", "gentileza"] },
      { "question" : "pretty good", "answers" : ["muito bom"] }
    ]
  },

  {
    "topic" : "NEW WORDS PART 04",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "ready", "answers" : ["pronto"] },
      { "question" : "avoid", "answers" : ["evitar"] },
      { "question" : "void", "answers" : ["vazio"] },
      { "question" : "barefoot", "answers" : ["descalco", "sem sapato"] },
      { "question" : "almost", "answers" : ["quase"] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] }
    ]
  },


  {
    "topic" : "Upper Intermediate ",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "sightseeing", "answers" : ["visiting interesting places"] },
      { "question" : "hold", "answers" : ["to take and keep something in your hand or arms"] },
      { "question" : "rather than", "answers" : ["instead of; used especially when you prefer one thing to another", "\nEx: I think I'd like to stay at home this evening rather than go out."] },
      { "question" : "affluent", "answers" : ["having a lot of money or owning a lot of things", "affluent nations/neighbourhoods"] },
      { "question" : "stunning", "answers" : ["extremely beautiful or attractive", "\na stunning dress", "\na stunning view over the bay of Saint Tropez"] },
      { "question" : "up-and-coming", "answers" : ["likely to achieve success soon or in the near future", "\nHe's a up-and-coming musician with no criminal history", "\nNew York magazine says this is the new up-and-coming neighborhood"] },
      { "question" : "trendy", "answers" : ["modern and influenced by the most recent fashions or ideas", "\nHotel La Fresque is only 5 minutes drive from the trendy Puerto Madero"] },
      { "question" : "grand", "answers" : ["important and large in degree", "\nShe has all kinds of grand ideas.", "\nHis job has a grand title, but he's little more than a clerk."] },
      { "question" : "high-rise", "answers" : ["a tall modern building with many floors","\nMany high-rise apartments are seen in Seoul.", "\nShe lives in a high-rise overlooking the river."] },
      { "question" : "historic", "answers" : ["important or likely to be important in history", "\nhistoric buildings"] },
      { "question" : "residential", "answers" : ["A residential road, area, etc. has only private houses, not offices and factories", "\nApartment located in a very quiet residential area in Monção", "\nSituated in residential area close to the sea"] },
      { "question" : "rough", "answers" : ["dangerous or violent" ,"\na rough area of town"] },
      { "question" : "deprived", "answers" : ["not having the things that are necessary for a pleasant life, such as enough money, food, or good living conditions", "\na deprived area"] },
      { "question" : "run-down", "answers" : ["buildings or areas are in very bad condition"] },
      { "question" : "hideous", "answers" : ["extremely ugly or bad", "\nThey've just built some hideous new apartment blocks on the seafront."] },
      { "question" : "steer clear", "answers" : ["avoid", "\nI suggest you steer clear for a while."] },
      { "question" : "soar", "answers" : ["go up very fast" , "\nApparently the price of bananas has soared"] },
      { "question" : "renovate", "answers" : ["to repair and improve something, especially a building", "\nThe building was renovated in 2010"] },
      { "question" : "knocked down", "answers" : ["destroy, demolish", "\nSomeone knocked down Mr. Hawk's house."] },
      { "question" : "dominate", "answers" : ["be much bigger than other places"] },
      { "question" : "huge", "answers" : ["extremely large in size or amount", "\nThey live in a huge house"] },
      { "question" : "date back", "answers" : ["go back in time"] },
      { "question" : "wealthy", "answers" : ["rich"] },
      { "question" : "boost", "answers" : ["to improve or increase something", "\nThe theatre managed to boost its audiences by cutting ticket prices"] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] },
      { "question" : "", "answers" : [""] }
    ]
  },


  {
    "topic" : "TEST",
    "list" : [
      { "question" : "break", "answers" : ["broke", "broken"] },
      { "question" : "kill", "answers" : ["matar"] },
      { "question" : "xxxxx", "answers" : [""] }
    ]
  }
]